Steffen Riber Thomsen

Lead Software Developer with broad experiences within software development. Bringing forth 7+ years of providing technical guidance and successfully executing engineering designs, including design, implementation, verification, and validation. Adept in overseeing all aspects of software projects, versatile team player who loves working with people.

Solimanvej 4 2770 Kastrup (+45) 22279014 riber4@gmail.com www.riber.dev



EXPERIENCE

Naviair, Kastrup — *Lead Software Developer*

09/2021 - PRESENT

I worked as a swiss army knife at Naviair, where I took on the responsibility as a Software Lead helping my team grow as a unit and write better solutions. A Product Owner helping planning and scoping projects with our Business Management. A Software and Cloud Architect with focus on DevOps and CI/CD structure.

Terma A/S, Herlev — Lead Software Developer

04/2018 - 09/2021

I was put as responsible lead for the Product team whose main focus was to revamp the Combat Management System (C-Flex) to an easier accessible system that is minded towards Patrol and light vessels and their missions. My work included leading the team towards its goals, and improving its overall quality as a software team. This included requirement analysis, technical research, system and software design.

Terma A/S, Herlev — Software Developer

10/2014 - 04/2018

My work included developing new features, maintaining and improving the Combat Management System (C-Flex) for the Royal Danish Navy. I worked mainly with Java doing full stack development, which included both system integration towards different sensors and sub-systems and UI/UX development.

Elsiver, Aalborg — System Administrator

09/2013 - 07/2014

My work included the operation and maintenance of hardware and software, which included both local and cloud services running Microsoft Windows and different Linux OS. Database development, administration and installation on Oracle Database, Microsoft SQL Server and PostgreSQL. Customer software installation and upgrade which was either done manually or guided.

SKILLS

Java, TypeScript, Node.js, React.js, MongoDB, Linux, SQL/NoSQL, Microsoft Azure, SCRUM/Agile, DevOps, CI/CD, Docker, Software Architecture, Cloud Computing, Serverless, Event Driven Design

AWARDS

Internet Quality - more than bandwidth - Invited to present at a conference by Collaboration Living Labs (COLL) - 2012

Nominated at ing.dk product award for the NetMap project - 2012

Present at IUCC2012 in Liverpool - with IEEE article "Location Assisted Vertical Handover Algorithm for QoS Optimization in End-to-End Connections" - 2012

LANGUAGES

Danish (Native fluency)
English (Fluent / Bilingual)

Aalborg University, Aalborg— Student Helper (Network & Security)

Summer 2011

Worked on designing and analyzing potential malicious network attacks on a deployed Intelligent Transport Systems in collaboration with Gatehouse Aalborg A/S.

EDUCATION

Aalborg University, Aalborg — Master of Science (M.Sc.) in Network & Distributed Systems

2011 - 2013

Thesis: "Analysis and Improvement of Network Performance Measurement Procedures for Android Devices".

- Thesis focuses on thorough analysis and testing of network performance measurement techniques tailored for use on mobile devices and cellular networks.
- Main focus has been on measuring and analysis of Network
 Performance and Quality of Service. The analysis has been done using
 empirical data gathered by a self-designed Android application
 named "NetMap".

Aalborg University, Aalborg— Bachelor of Science (B.Sc.) in Computer Engineering with Specialization in Communication Systems

2008 - 2011

Thesis: "In-line Detection of Distributed Denial of Service Attacks on Core Networks".

 Thesis deals with analysis of DDoS attacks and how one can prevent such. Topics such as: Software and Network Design with focus on interaction between hardware, software and human. Embedded real-time systems and complex distributed system design with robust communication.